

Oakville, ON L6M 5N4 | 1 902-719-7238 | dennis.liu1224@outlook.com

Summary

I have 13 years of expertise helping students who wanted to study abroad in English-speaking nations like Canada, the United States of America, Britain, Australia, and New Zealand with professional guidance and solutions. Over the past ten years, I have directly aided over a hundred Chinese students with their academic planning for studying abroad and their admissions applications.

I started my career in international education services by working for one of the largest immigration and international education service providers in China since 2009 and continued there until June 2012. I had many opportunities during this time to speak with admissions representatives from various higher education institutions in North America and Europe, and as a result, I developed a solid understanding about the philosophies of colleges and universities as well as their admission standards and procedures.

In July 2012, I made the decision to work for myself as a freelancer in international education services in China. I cooperated with a leading organization, which provides strategic solutions for overseas institutions in student recruitment, joint venture programs, study tours and international education exhibitions, in China. Relying on this organization's robust overseas higher-education partnership networks, and integrating with my own abundant experience, I assisted over a hundred students to be admitted into their dream schools, 70% of which were accepted by Canadian colleges and universities.

In 2018, my family and I moved to Canada, and I've been continuing to be self-employed. Now I'd like to change my future career from freelancing to working as an international admission specialist. I think I'll be qualified for the position because I'm excellent at:

- International student programs of Canadian Colleges.
- Admission requirements and procedures.
- Strong communication abilities and experience working with foreign agents or students directly.
- Solving issues and giving guidance to students during their application processes.
- Experienced in delivering program training to overseas agents for any updates pertaining to the programs at Centennial College.
- Experienced in participating in international education exhibitions in overseas markets, such as China.

Please look through my CV and the specifics of my prior professional experience in the attachment. If you need any additional information on my experience or have any queries, don't hesitate to get in touch with me. I would be delighted to meet with you and go over the specifics of the role.

Thank you for your consideration.

Skills

- Interpersonal and Written Communication
- Customer Service
- Good Presentation Skills

- Education Plans
- Student Assessments
- Years of Student Service Experience

Experience

INTERNATIONAL EDUCATION CONSULTANT | 07/2018 - 10/2022

Self-Employed - Oakville/Halifax, ON/NS

- Collaborate with authorized agents of Canadian colleges and universities, public school boards and independent and boarding schools, to promote academic programs to students in China mainland.
- Help channel partners (consulting agents) in China to provide expert, thorough and accurate information regarding school selection, admission, application and settlement services to clients; and propose one-stop and customized application services based on target students' educational background, academic strength, career goal and hobbies
- Work closely with case managers and processors of consulting agents in China to develop practical and expert application strategies for students, ensuing that their submissions satisfy the criteria set forth by certain colleges and universities for admission.
- Offer dependable relocation services, such as airport pickup, apartment rental, school orientation, etc., to students coming from Chinese partner agents.

INTERNATIONAL EDUCATION CONSULTANT | 06/2012 - 06/2018

Self-Employed - Tianjin/Beijing/Shanghai

- Collaborate with authorized agents of Canadian colleges and universities, public school boards and independent and boarding schools, to promote academic programs to students in China mainland.
- Help channel partners (consulting agents) in China to provide expert, thorough and accurate information regarding school selection, admission, application and settlement services to clients; and propose one-stop and customized application services based on target students' educational background, academic strength, career goal and hobbies.
- Work closely with case managers and processors of consulting agents in China to develop practical and expert application strategies for students, ensuing that their submissions satisfy the criteria set forth by certain colleges and universities for admission.
- Offer dependable relocation services, such as airport pickup, apartment rental, school orientation, etc., to students coming from Chinese partner agents.
- Work with designated agents to participate in various forms of international education exhibitions held in China to promote relevant programs and services to potential partner agents and targeted clients.

Achievement:

- 1. Developed a wide partner agents' network and established long-term and stable cooperation with them around China.
- 2. Helped over hundreds of Chinese students to be admitted into public school boards and private independent schools of Canada, and Canadian colleges and universities as well, by offering professional and customized one-stop consulting, application and settlement services.

CONSULTANT & CASE PROCESSOR | 12/2009 - 06/2012

Well Trend United Consulting Inc. - Beijing, Beijing/China

- Work with partnered Canadian Immigration Lawyer and firms to deliver accurate, updated and professional
 immigration consultation to clients, and work out most feasible immigration solutions to clients based on their various
 backgrounds.
- Work with closely with case processors to help clients to prepare necessary and requested immigration documents and receive feedbacks and all updates about submitted cases from Immigration Lawyers.
- Assist marketing department in promoting international settlement services on various industry exhibitions.

• Work with local settlement services providers in Canada to arrange and deliver pre-arrival service packages to successful clients and make sure their settlements in Canada can run smoothly.

Education and Training

Singapore AIT Academy - Singapore | Diploma in Information Technology